Nature Conservancy in Arizona records, 1884-1999
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup 2: Site Files, 1884-1997, 7.30 linear feet (approximately 14,600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  - Series 18: Hassayampa River Preserve, 1986-1994, .30 linear feet (approximately 600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    - Subseries 2: Ecology, 1986
      - Project Summary-Lykes Tract. 1986 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Subseries 3: Protection and Management, 1986-1993
      - Reports-Pollen Analysis and Palm Lake Renovation. 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Series 19: Holbrook NE Site, 1981, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (1981). The file documents the management of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, 1981
      - Arizona Site Summary. 1981 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Series 20: Jak Ranch, 1988, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Ecology (1988). The file documents the ecological resources of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1988
      - Ecological Summary and Stewardship. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Series 21: Kino Springs, 1978-1989, undated, .07 linear feet (approximately 140 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    Arrangement: alphabetical. This series contains two subseries: Correspondence (1978-1989) and Photographs and Images (undated). Files document the general correspondence and physical characteristics of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1978-1989, undated
      - General. 1978-1989 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Subseries 2: Photographs and Image, s undated
      - General. undated (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Series 22: Kiper Springs, 1979-1989, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (1979-1989). The file documents the establishment and management of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, 1979-1989
      - Establishment Proposal. 1979-1989 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Series 23: Leslie Spring, 1986-1988, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains two subseries: Ecology (1986-1988) and Protection and Management (1986-1988). Files document the ecological resources and management of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1986-1988
      - Ecological Summary and Stewardship. 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Subseries 2: Protection and Management, 1986-1988
      - Project Summary. 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Series 24: McDowell Mountains, 1995, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Correspondence (1985). The file documents the correspondence related to the planning and management of the DC Ranch at the site.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1985
      - DC Ranch Planning. 1995 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Series 25: Muleshoe Ranch Cooperative Management Area, 1884-1997, .65 linear feet (approximately 1,300 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains four subseries: Administration (1949-1997), Ecology (1983), History and Archaeology (1884-1990), and Protection and Management (1982-1991). Files document the fiscal administration and reporting activities, land appraisal and acquisition, ecological resources, historical research, archaeological resources, and protection and management of the cooperative management area.
    - Subseries 1: Administration, 1949-1997
      - Fiscal-Annual Operating Budget. 1989 (Box 10, Folder 61)
      - Grant Application-Watershed Improvement to Restore Riparian and Aquatic Habitat. 1997 (Box 10, Folder 62)
      - Grant Application-Watershed Improvement to Restore Riparian and Aquatic Habitat. 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Land-Bass Canyon Addition and Acquisition. 1949-1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Land-Muleshoe Ranch Appraisal and Acquisition. 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Land-Patterson Ranch Appraisal. 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Reports-Annual and Quarterly. 1983-1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Subseries 2: Ecology, 1983
      - Biological Survey of Muleshoe Ranch. 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Subseries 3: History and Archaeology, 1884-1990
      - Architectural History and Chronology. 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Arizona State Museum Archaeological Survey and Prehistory Outline. 1941-1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - History Project-Brief History of the Bass Canyon Addition and Pride Ranch. 1952-1987 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - History Project-Brief History of the Muleshoe Ranch Preserve, Final and Draft. 1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - History Project-Geology and Mining History in the Galiuro Mountains. undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - History Project-Hooker Hot Springs Film Script Outline and Research Notes. 1985-1990 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - History Project-Hooker Hot Springs Research. 1884-1988 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - History Project-"Life and Death of Hooker's Hot Springs: 1876-1906", Mills, T. F. 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - History Project-Research on Browning, James Ernest (1953-1972). 1978-1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - History Project-Research on Isaacson, Deming W. (1906- 1927) and Muleshoe Ranch. 1917-1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - History Project-Research on King, Dr. Glendy (1875- 1884). 1981-1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - History Project-Research on Kittle, Jake. 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - History Project-Research on McMurray, Jessica (1927- 1950). 1950-1990 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - History Project-Research on Muleshoe Ranch and Surrounding Areas. 1901-1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - History Project-Research on Wilson, Richard F. (1975- Present). 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Research-General and Chronology. 1978-1989 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Research-Spanish Period. 1953-1987 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Subseries 4: Protection and Management, 1982-1991
      - Preserve Plans. 1982-1991 (Box 11, Folder 24-26)
      - Soza Mesa Proposal. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Series 26: Oracle State Park, 1973-1989, .80 linear feet (approximately 1,600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains five subseries: Administration (1973-1989), Correspondence (1984-1987), History and Archaeology (1980), Photographs and Images (1982-1985), and Protection and Management (1976-1989). Files document the Defenders of Wildlife Board of Trustees meetings, resolutions, fiscal administration, land and other property-related documents, general correspondence, Kannally Ranch historical chronology, physical characteristics, and management plans and projects of the state park.
    - Subseries: Administration, 1973-1989
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1975 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1976 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1978 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1980 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1982 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes and Agendas. 1983 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Defenders of Wildlife Trust-Board of Trustees Resolutions. 1973-1983 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Fiscal-Defenders of Wildlife Accounts Ledger. 1977-1982 (Box 11, Folder 38-40)
      - Fiscal-Expense Documentation. 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Gaona, Fermin-Release Agreement. 1977-1987 (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Inventory and Transfer of Lee Kannally Paintings. 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 43)
      - Kannally Bequest Report and Estate Documents. 1976-1985 (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Land-Appraisal Report. 1985 (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - Land-Deed, Memorandum of Understanding and Transfer to Arizona State Parks. 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 46)
      - Land-Grazing Lease and Livestock Brand Certificate. 1975-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Land-Inventory of Kannally Property and Mineral Titles. 1976-1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Land-Lease Agreement. 1976-1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Land-Property Insurance. 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Land-Restrictive Covenants and Property Tax Statements. 1976-1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Land-Transfer to Arizona State Parks. 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1984-1987
      - General. 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Subseries 3: History and Archaeology, 1980
      - Kannally Ranch History Chronology. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Subseries 4: Photographs and Images, 1982-1985
      - Kannally Ranch. 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Subseries 5: Protection and Management, 1976-1989
      - All American Pipeline Project Right of Way. 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Master Plan Reports and News Clippings. 1976-1989 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
      - Oracle Education Project. 1979-1986 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Series 27: Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Preserve, 1965-1993, undated, .60 linear feet (approximately 1,200 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains six subseries: Administration (1965-1993), Correspondence (1965-1982), History and Archaeology (undated), Photographs and Images (1992), and Protection and Management (1966-1991). Files document the fiscal operations and reporting activities, general correspondence, ecological resources, historic and prehistoric resources, physical characteristics, and protection and management plans and proposals of the preserve.
    - Subseries 1: Administration, 1965-1993
      - Fiscal-Annual Operating Budget and Plan. 1981-1991 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Fiscal-Expense Documentation. 1965-1967 (Box 12, Folder 15-17)
      - Fiscal-Expense Documentation. 1968-1981 (Box 12, Folder 18-22)
      - Reports-Annual and Quarterly. 1977-1993 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Reports to Contributors. 1968-1987 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1965-1982
      - General. 1965-1982 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Subseries 3: Ecology, undated
      - "Aquatic Biota of the Sonoita Creek Basin." 1967-1980 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - "Established Natural Areas in Arizona, A Guidebook for Scientists and Educators." 1974-1980 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Hydrologic Report, Plant and Wildlife Lists Handbook. 1967-1971 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Plant and Wildlife Elements Spreadsheet. undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Subseries 4: History and Archaeology, undated
      - Sonoita Creek Historic and Prehistoric Site Lists. undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Subseries 5: Photographs and Images, 1982
      - General. 1992 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Subseries 6: Protection and Management, 1981-1985
      - Arizona Site Summary and Site Stewardship Summaries. 1981-1985 (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Management Plan, Flood Insurance and Zoning. 1969-1979 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Management Plan Outline. 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Master Plan for Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Sanctuary and Site Stewardship Summaries. 1975-1991 (Box 12, Folder 36-37)
      - Natural Area Project Proposal. 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Series 28: Ramsey Canyon Preserve, 1953-1993, 1.20 linear feet (approximately 2,400 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    . This series includes four subseries: Administration (1959-1993), Correspondence (1953-1981), Ecology (1973-1985), and Protection and Management (1971-1991). Files document the fiscal, land acquisition, property taxes, and reporting activities, correspondence related to fundraising, the Mile Hi Ranch and stewardship, ecological resources, and the protection, management, and use of the preserve.
    - Subseries 1: Administration, 1959-1993
      - Fiscal-Budget Related. 1976-1989 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - Fiscal-Expense Documentation. 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Fiscal-Fundraising for Mile Hi Ranch Purchase. 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Fiscal-Operating Procedures and Related Forms. 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Fiscal-Operating Statements and Inventory Summaries. 1976-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - General. 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
      - Land-Bethel, Nell Irene Brown, Release Agreement. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Land-Bledsoe Property, General. 1972-1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Land-Bledsoe Will and Peabody Property Purchase Option. 1959-1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Land-Property Taxes and Exemptions. 1975-1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Reports-Annual and Quarterly. 1977-1993 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Reports-Monthly Activities. 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1953-1981
      - Fundraising. 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
      - Mile Hi Ranch. 1953-1977 (Box 13, Folder 17-19)
      - Stewardship. 1960-1976 (Box 13, Folder 20-24)
      - Stewardship. 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Stewardship. 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Subseries 3: Ecology, 1973-1985
      - Mile Hi Ranch-"Birds of Mile Hi Ranch" and General Plant and Wildlife Information. 1973-1977 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - Special Element Plant Maps, International Biological Programme Survey and Bird List. 1980-1985 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Subseries 4: Protection and Management, 1971-1991
      - General. 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 29-30)
      - Masterplan and Site Stewardship Summaries. 1976-1988 (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Mile Hi Ranch-General. 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 32-33)
      - Mile Hi Ranch-Project Acquisition Proposal. undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Preserve Use-Birdwatching. 1977-1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Preserve Use-Brochures. 1980-1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Preserve Use-Media and Publicity. 1977-1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Preserve Use-Signage. 1975-1983 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Preserve Use-Trails. 1977-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Preserve Use-Vandalism and Trespass. 1976-1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Preserve Use-Visitor Policies, Survey and General Information. 1971-1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Proposal for Application of Herbicide to Control Vinca major. 1986 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Report-Environmental Assessment on Proposed Access Road. 1979 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Series 29: Rio Yaqui Headwaters System, 1983, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Ecology (1983). The file documents the ecological resources of the headwater system.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1983
      - Report-Threatened Fish Species. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Series 30: Sabino Creek Macrosite, undated, .03 linear feet (approximately 60 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (undated). Files document the protection and management of three areas or tracts of the macrosite.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, undated
      - Sabino Creek-Project Package Module. undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Simons Tract-Project Package Checklist. undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Timken Tract-Project Package Checklist. undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Series 31: San Bernardino Ranch Site, 1979-1983, .05 linear feet (approximately 100 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains three subseries: Administration (1979-1982), Ecology (1981-1983), and Protection and Management (1979). Files document the land transfer and taxes, ecological resources, and protection and management of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Administration, 1979-1982
      - Fiscal-Taxes and Land Transfer. 1979-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Subseries 2: Ecology, 1981-1983
      - Report- "Vertebrates of San Bernardino Ranch, Cochise County, Arizona." 1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Special Plants and Wildlife List. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Subseries 3: Protection and Management, 1979
      - Project Acquisition Proposal. 1979 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Series 32: San Francisco Peaks Site, 1988, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    . This series contains two subseries: Ecology (1988) and Protection and Management (1988). Files document the ecological resources and protection and management visits for the site.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1988
      - Ecological Summary. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Subseries 2: Protection and Management, 1988
      - Visit Summary. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Series 33: San Pedro River Biopreserve, 1973-1998, .30 linear feet (approximately 600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    . This series contains four subseries: Administration (1992), Correspondence (1978-1985), Ecology (1973-1998), and Protection and Management (1979-1992). Files document land acquisition, general correspondence, ecological resources, and protection and management plans, projects, proposals and reports of the biopreserve.
    - Subseries 1: Administration, 1992
      - Land-Property Costs. 1992 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1978-1985
      - General. 1978-1985 (Box 14, Folder 22-23)
    - Subseries 3: Ecology, 1973-1998
      - Arizona Highways- "The San Pedro Riparian Area." 1989 (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Reports on Plant, Wildlife, and Ecosystem Acquisition. 1973-1978 (Box 14, Folder 25-26)
      - San Pedro Basin Arid Ecosystems Study-EMAP. 1995-1998 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Subseries 4: Protection and Management, 1979-1992
      - Executive Order Statement of Mission and Purpose, Draft. undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - Land Protection Action Plan. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - Media and Publicity. 1991-1995 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - North American Free Trade Agreement Review. 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Report-Environmental Assessment and Proposed Land Acquisition. 1979 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - San Pedro River Ecosystem Project. 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Strategic Plan and Land and Water Conservation Fund Proposal. 1989-1996 (Box 14, Folder 34-35)
      - Summary-Fiscal Year 1992. 1992 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Series 34: San Rafael Valley Macrosite, 1980, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Ecology (1980). Files document the ecological resources of the macrosite.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1980
      - Plant Communities and Endangered Species List. 1980 (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - Report-"Grassland Survey of the San Rafael Valley." 1980 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Series 35: Santa Rita Experimental Range, 1987, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (1987). The file documents the land exchange resolution and protection and management of the experimental range.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, 1987
      - Land Swap Draft Resolution and Publicity. 1987 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Series 36: Tavasci Marsh Site, 1973-1993, .06 linear feet (approximately 120 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains two subseries: Photographs and Images (1973-1989) and Protection and Management (1988-1993). Files document the physical characteristics and protection and management of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Photographs and Images, 1973-1989
      - Slides. 1973-1989 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Subseries 2: Protection and Management, 1988-1993
      - Environmental Assessment Review, Correspondence and Policy. 1988-1993 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Series 37: Tumamoc Hill Site, 1987-1990, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: History and Archaeology (1987-1990). The file documents the nomination of the nomination for the historical and archaeological resources of the site.
    - Subseries 1: History and Archaeology, 1987-1990
      - Desert Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution-National Register of Historical Places Inventory Nomination Form.. 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Series 38: Vekol Valley Special Management Area, 1988, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains two subseries: Ecology (1988) and Protection and Management (1988). Files document the ecological resources and protection and management visits of the special management area.
    - Subseries 1: Ecology, 1988
      - Site Ecological Summary. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Subseries 2: Protection and Management, 1988
      - Visit Summary. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Series 39: Volunteer Canyon-Smith Road Site, 1988-1990, .04 linear feet (approximately 80 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (1988-1990). The file documents the protection and management evaluation and access decisions of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, 1988-1990
      - Biological Evaluation and Access Request Impact Decision Notice. 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Series 40: Waterman Mountains Site, 1986-1988, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Protection and Management (1986-1988). The file documents the management of a species of cacti at the site.
    - Subseries 1: Protection and Management, 1986-1988
      - Report-Nichol Turk's Head Cactus Habitat Management Plan. 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Series 41: White Canyon, 1989, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Correspondence (1989). The file documents the general correspondence of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1989
      - General. 1989 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Series 42: Whitewater Draw, 1991, .01 linear feet (approximately 20 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains one subseries: Photographs and Images (1991). The file documents the physical characteristics of the site.
    - Subseries 1: Photographs and Images, 1991
      - General. 1991 (Box 14, Folder 48)